YouTube Guest Thanks, how many people has this
Digital Transformation of India
helped? 70000 is coming, so
yours is 70000, but somewhere,
it's basically an
insurance, what is it? It's not like we have to pay 70000, it's not that
costly.
I have an option to get
back the 70000 that was my first for as
I know this is only for maternity
delivery. I was extremely happy. Hey
guys, welcome back to my channel. This
is Anusha. We are so happy today. I am making a
video to give you all some useful
information. This will be a mix of
both Kannada and English. If you
specifically want it in Kannada or in
English.  Separately, let me know in the
comment so that I can give you the
information in the language that you
choose, either Kannada or English. So,
I came to make this video because it is very useful. So, you
came to make the video after a long time. Because this is
a very important information. I did not know it either.
So, I came to know
after the experience. So, you are
doing this. In this video, I
mix English and Kannada. If you specifically
want English, but specifically in Kannada, then tell
me in the comments. So, I will make a
separate video for you and upload it. And again, it
depends on the response. So, what is the reason for today? So, today, I have seen all
my previous videos. If you
have  Watched all my previous videos
so made be the birth of my second child
experience that I had in the
Bangalore Baptist Hospital so
Bangalore Baptist Hospital
and the facility how the room looked and
all of that so have
you seen all those videos Andre Nandu delivery ugly
baby how the
room was how the service was all that
video then
several other videos of my kid also
like the baby massage the food that is used
for the post partum care for the mother have you
seen all that so today I have come here
to give you all an important
information which is about the
insurance so one scenario explain
so both husband  Let's assume that both of us have
corporate insurance. In my
experience, I and my husband are both working. Both of us have
corporate
insurance. So now, legally,
we have an option where in both of you
can claim your medical
insurance for the hospital bill only
for maternity. So, maternity is when the
delivery happens, one of you has
no insurance claim and the other has
insurance claim. So there is an option
where both of you can get insurance and
both of you can claim through the legal process of insurance. So,
I have come to explain that today. First,
I will give you some background.
We went to Bangalore Baptist Hospital.
My husband is a big
corporate MNC. Big MNC.
One of the biggest in India.
I work in an MNC. I
work in a company. It is a French-
based MNC. My husband is an
Indian-based MNC. My husband has
insurance. I also have insurance. So I mean, their
corporate insurance is a
little more than the cab. It is a little
less than the cab. Our office
has given this amount by default.
Within that amount, I claim for the entire
family. So if I need it, I can enroll my
husband, my kids, my parents, all in-
laws. There is an
option in my office. I have
enrolled my parents. So it
means my insurance is valid for
me, my husband, my kids, my kids, and
my parents. My husband's insurance is also valid for
his wife and this is also
valid for his spouse, kids, and
parents.  So,
what else do they have, they get a
domiciliary claim, I don't have a domiciliary claim, that's the difference,
but their amount is very high, it's
5 lakhs today, it's the same, theirs is over 5
lakhs, theirs is over 12 lakhs per head, it's more, that's it, their
insurance
is so fine, we are all hospital full, for us Baptist Hospital is very, it's very far, we are very far from our
house,
Baptist Hospital is in
Hebbal, so you can see
Bangalore Baptist Hospital, but
we were comfortable, there was a doctor and
we went here, it's
almost 20 kilometers from our house, we
are in KR Pura, you
will know if you watch my videos there, so
from starting to end, all the
consultation, even the
delivery, was there, the delivery was there.  That's it,
now what's next? They
told us to start today and go and inquire about insurance. They didn't say anything and
we went and asked from the initiative. There are three options. When
you are admitted to the hospital, there are three options. One is that you have to
pay the money yourself and come outside. The
other is that you have to claim the insurance as cashless. The other is that you have to pay the money and come there and get the
reimbursement of those bills.
What is this option? The reimbursement and
cashless option is only for those who
have insurance or
no corporate health insurance. Those who have personal health
insurance have their own options.
So when we went and inquired, I said, "
What are you doing, Miss Agbardu?" and I hoped that I would give you the
correct
information. So when we went, we went.  Ask
them and we got to know that my
husbands insurance first we
first what we did we
checked our insurance we usually
charged 75000 for delivery most of the
companies as far as i know after
working for so many years it is always 75000
for c section 50000 for normal
delivery so but my husbands company
said that insurance is good
what did they do I will not be able to
disclose the name of the insurance
because this is not any paid
promotion I will be my husbands
office is a bit ugly so I have to ask
them a bit and give information then and
i am ready to give it to IC
Lombard so then 75 for c section
50000 for normal delivery, some
hospital gives me this much,
my husband said that his is 1000, it
depends on the designation also,
so he gives 1000 for C-section,
75000 for normal delivery, who gives this,
I didn't ask, no, this is the first
time I asked, there was no last time, she was
my grandmother's daughter, first name, daughter, if she wanted to deliver, she did
n't give birth, so this time it is
1000, 75000, our cap was
theirs, so firstly I went and inquired, then I
found out that my husband has 1000,
obviously if anything more comes,
I will claim more, let's unlock it, okay, let's go there,
my husband
said let's go there, then I went
there  There is
an insurance department in every hospital. When I went
there and asked, they
said, "What is my husband's insurance?
It's not here. So you can get a re-
embossment." They
said, "Fine." They said, "
We have to pay for the re-embossment here. Even
though the credit card is such a huge amount, we are afraid that we don't have that much cash.
So let's pay through the credit card." I said, "
Okay, fine, there is a cap of 1000. Let's
go through it." I said, "What did I do?
Obtain my husband's insurance.
There, when you select insurance, they ask for
your insurance ID, policy
number, and Aadhaar card. What
documents do you need to provide?" I said, "
My husband is not there. The hospital is
not there. It is cashless, but I don't want to
because there is a cap."
Then I decided.  Okay, let's pay the bill and
then get reimbursed. This is our
first decision. First decision. What we
did was okay. Let's use my husband's insurance and
then get reimbursed.
We have never had so much
hospitalization. But
we had never had a single incident.
Our mom and dad were our parents.
We
didn't do it. So first time, okay, let's try. They
said reimbursement. So fine. They didn't
give any details. You gave us the bill. We lost the bill. They
said they would reimburse us there. So you gave us the
information. Here is the
limit. What was our background? The
fine came. The date my child
was born on the 12th was March 12. As you know,
day by day. I posted a video on March
12th.  I was admitted and I had 9th BP and I just wanted to give
you a very small
information of the background. What
happened after that? 15 We were discharged. The
baby was born on the third day. I
think the bill
date is 15. So when we were discharged, they went to
take the bill and came back. This is the bill.
You go to the finance department and pay it. So I looked at the
bill. What is the bill now? The
first day is the bill.
My maternity. What did they take care of on the day of my delivery?
That's plus the
in-case the baby has NIC. If there is anything wrong with the baby,
it will be a separate bill. Did they
go to the NICU? We were also
taken directly. Our jaundice was
borderline there. So there was
no need for NICU. We had one
day of phototherapy. One and a half days of
phototherapy.  There is a bill for it, it is a
little bit because they
put everything in that bassinet, so there are
charges for it, so they
gave us two bills, two bills. I will post the
photos here. I will post the
photos here. So I will tell you how much it cost. So let's
open this is my
file. This is mostly Kannada and English, so anyone who uses
any language will understand. If you don't understand
something,
please comment and let me know. So
first let me talk about my bill. Okay, so this
is this photo. You can
see how much the bill is.
I have some details on the same photo. I am
covering it.
How much is the bill? It is
133000 and 115. So it includes
anesthesia, bed charge, miscellaneous
nursing care, OT charge, pharmacy, all together.
All this is detailed
information given to us, what
blood was done, what blood test was done, what
was used for which surgery, how much medicine, pharmacy bills,
so all that is detailed, what is the bifurcation given to us here, every detail of it, what was used
for the hospital procedure, what was the lab
test done, everything was
given to us, so this was very
transparent, we did not have a little bit of an error here and there,
everything was correct, so
I know how much the total is,
that
143759 paise, of which the hospital discount is
85 paise, so the total I have to pay is
131305 74 paise,
add GST to it, that is the GST Goods
and Service Tax for the hospital too.
We paid goods and GST
30 paise so what is the total
13315 so the total bill was
13315 for me alone ok this is my bill
this is my husband has to pay who
ever is paying the bill this will be
paid by us again there will be a baby bill so I will
show you the baby bill this is baby
of Anusha we did not give any other name
then this is baby's bill this foot I
will say I see here
so baby all together 15000
17395 in which
discount 1477
net amount to be paid
15915 so the baby's bill is
15915 so totally almost 133 + 115
so how much is our total bill
almost 150  It came to 150 1000 2000
more 2000 more or less so this
was our bill the same details same what was
said same what was done here
its bill is
given in detail so this is about our bill we got this then we were
discharged then we went and paid then
a discharge summary came and after
giving it to the nurse they explain
how to take medicines they explain
discharge summary
then we are allowed to go out
all the hospital there rules fine all are same
we came home so what did we ask today why is the
bill from 9th to 15th only
not from 12th to 15th so 9th I
was admitted 15th I was discharged so
9th  From 12th to 15th, my child got 133000,
from 12th to 15th, it got 16000, 100
less, that's it, now we paid this,
paid through credit card,
came home, what did we find out,
my husband has one lakh, so
133000, the child and the woman will come separately, it is
not included in the allowance, so
we knew that all the claims will be made, then
133 days later, my husband will get 1000,
another 33000, that's it, everything was
fine, let alone these days, I
thought, it's all fine, the
hospital has
given us what documents, they
ask for insurance there, this bill has been
discharged, basically there is a set of
documents  What's wrong, my sample has been
stabilized, my husband
uploaded this much bill and got fined,
so he uploaded everything, but after uploading
everything, we get a claim for a certain amount, when
that amount is claimed, we
saw how much that amount was
claimed for us, my husband's
insurance company made a claim for 63000,
we were completely shocked, so 133
there was 63000, so count it yourself,
73 83 93 103 113 123 133, almost 70000,
we paid by hand, so fine,
what's this, we paid 70000, it's not that it's
so costly, I was
completely confused, I
don't know how much my husband got confused, he got so confused  It didn't
look like it was going to be bad, Bikas
didn't talk about it, but the amount was so much, okay,
what can we do, what else can we do, I
said, "Fine," and no one told us, "
This is insurance, this is another insurance,
we don't know what information we use. Until now, we
were blank. I
gave you the background, but you
are blank. We don't know anything. So fine, I am at
my mother's house. It's not like
I have to pay 70,000. It's not like it's so
costly. The
baby was not in the NICU.
I was healthy. I had some BP
fluctuations. So,
instead of giving 1,000, they gave me only 63,
not 133. I was a little
annoyed. Fine, I was doing
some research when I was  I am doing some
research through YouTube so I have to
thank YouTube so much. This digital
transformation of India has
helped so many people. I feel like I am like this.
Because before YouTube, the
internet was not so easily accessible to us. I don't know if
I would have gotten that information or not.
What did I do? I used to have a
habit of typing my
questions. I put the full question on
Google. That habit is like that. I
type in Google
how to claim insurance.
That information is not coming to me at midnight. I am at two
o'clock or three o'clock. What happened?
So fine. When I went to Google,
I got a video. One YouTube
video. There are a few very few videos in each of them. There are five or
six videos.  I
sent the note to my husband too so he said
okay fine I have there is there is nothing which
I don't know and I
know it I will have to utilize it that is when I thought I have
to utilize this
information immediately the
next day I shared it because that was
midnight I had watched all those
videos and sent it to my husband and
then I I I spoke to my husband about the same there
is an option where we can
claim and get the money which we are
under loss where we are under loss of
70000 here so we have an option to
get back the 70000 that was mine  First
thought to my husband is that my husband is like do
more research don't go blindly do anything let's do what is
legal
I told him it's a legal thing I
watched videos I have seen there
documents I have spoken to the
customer care also so from that midnight
I talked to my husband the next day
within two or three hours I
called ICICI and asked them I had already received
confirmation so this is what
I said so for this basically I have to say
thanks to the internet
thanks a lot for Google and youtube
and all the people who share this kind of
information so I couldn't find that information even in
Kannada only
English there was also Hindi
so I didn't know  When
I shared something that was useful to Kannada people and ours,
ours saw it and said it was useful to them too.
So this is how it
started and then okay. What did
I know then? If I told you that if someone has
insurance, it is only for maternity. As for as
I know this is only for
maternity delivery. Let's say you
have corporate insurance, husband
and wife. Both of them
have corporate insurance. Both of them
can apply.
One of them has personal insurance. One has corporate
insurance because they are not
working. They said that it will happen to them too.
No, two people have personal insurance. So if
you
need information about this again and again,
customer care is always open 24/7. If
you ask for any insurance,
they will tell you okay.  First point is
both husband and wife either corporate
or personal insurance is
applicable to each other and this is applicable
only for maternity claims. For example, suppose there is a
huge heart
surgery. The big heart
surgery is 10 lakhs. Let's do husband and wife
insurance there. I am not sure
about it and I don't know about it also. As for as
I know, I am 99% sure.
This is only for maternity. I am
again stressing on the point. It is
for maternity alone. Then what
is the procedure? Okay, now you apply these
bills. Now that I have my child, I will talk to you later. When you
apply the bill, you
tell my husband.  When they
said 63000 was approved, it was approved.
So any insurance when it is
approved corporate or personal you get
something called as claim settlement
letter. So any insurance ugli you
get a claim settlement letter. That
claim settlement
letter is a copy that
you show as a proof to apply for another
insurance. Okay. So now what happened in my case?
My husband applied for his
insurance. He got 63000. His gap
was 1000. He got 63000. The remaining
70000 was not given to us by anyone. Then what we thought is
this insurance. Same
documents. My husband
uploaded those documents plus an
additional document that is.  Called
claim settlement letter which is issued
by his insurance I
have to take it and apply same documents plus an
additional document what I did
now same documents again
additional document but one more
you have to
remember here if you want to
claim claimed
requested amount are you claiming
for 133 expecting you get 1000 but if you want to
claim here it is not
133 that you are claiming so this second
insurance what happens to your documents there
first insurance there
documents were there but here you
claim for 133 which is the full
amount but here you claim
133 - 63 you already got so if you get caught then thats an
illegal
process  Which we are not supposed to do
legal process I am explaining
133 - 63 is what 70000 is not so if you
put 70000 claim then you should put
70000 so you put 70000
additional document that you put is
claim settlement letter so you will get this so now what
I did is
my husband came I did I
uploaded documents and this
is a legal procedure for maternity
claims alone where both husband and
wife can submit their bills and
claim settlement letter and get the money back
get the insurance insurance
money back so I uploaded it within two days
I got approval email within two days  Your
amount is approved out of 70000 67000
was approved so I saw that message
I don't have confidence what is this it didn't work before it didn't work
I was
completely shocked I was there it was just changed
again  Taree Yakandre
Insurance said that they would change it when we were in the hospital and that it would be
a bit confusing. I was there and then. That's why
I got a claim of 60 7000.
So my husband got 63 and
I got 67. So
what happened to the total? 130000. We got
130000. Then we got 3000 non-medical
expenses. They don't put
all the gloves, hokey and cotton. All those
non-medical expenses are not claimed.
So we got 130000 in total. This is it. Then I
thought, okay, super, it's not coming.
We didn't know that this is our table. This is our table. When
we were there, Manipal was there. When we were there,
2020 was 1000 1000.
We got a bill.  75000 My husband's insurance
came and left 25000 we 25000 30000
1000 5000 something happened and the bill so 25000
30000 something we paid If I knew then
mostly if I
knew the information then if I had done this kind of
research then I would have got the amount so I didn't know so
now I
know and implemented it so I got it I was extremely happy I
informed my husband
see
what happened tell me your friends tell me your friends
no my friends who needs
information let us give this who didn't give us
information so let us
go share this tell me if we share then
who got it my cousins
my brother my  The husband
also said in his office that this
is how you utilize your insurance in
a legal manner for maternity claims.
Okay, so this is my experience,
I shared my experience,
so what I said is that this is a legal
procedure, so there is no illegal
process in this, we are not
cheating on any insurance and this
is a very legal process. Now mostly 90,
80 to 90% of husbands and wives work, big
companies, small companies, they do
not give even 75000 for C-section.
So, if you use both of them, you can claim both of them and
say that your wife is not working now and send her to her parents'
house.
How many people have
insurance?  There are people who don't do it, don't do it,
when you
have insurance, utilize it, your parents are ugly, it's
wrong to spend money, it's not difficult, everyone is
difficult, so don't do it, if you have
insurance, now two people
work, two people claim, both of them
take the full amount, so it's ultimately a
husband and wife who work for
their children, for their family, so if you use
this kind of money, you will all benefit, watch
these kinds of videos,
watch informative videos, use it, you will benefit, no
one else will benefit, fine, this
is about my insurance, so it's very clear,
legally, you have a way to go for it,
okay, next time, if you talk, my child didn't
show me the bill, what is my child's bill to you?
15900 which is
15900 so what happened then normal
insurance full claim was 15900
there 5000 something bit 11000 my husband used it he did not
take insurance then he used only maternity then
15000 11000 claim was 5000 we paid by
our own hand so if you see total bill
133 there 131 33000 we paid
here 16 there 5000 we paid
whole delivery we
paid this much this is delivery this is whole
pregnancy not delivery then
we paid this much so that is
very good information everybody can
utilize some insurance my
Insurance has all the pre-posts there.
I didn't go to put the pre-posts. It's
not 67. I have to do it within 75. I didn't go to do it.
So somehow I didn't say anything. So there's
7000. And I don't have to pay all those bills.
It was a little
irritating. So I didn't want to do it.
So I wanted to do this video for a long time. Now
finally I think I got some
time to do it because my daughter
is sleeping now. Even I am on maternity
period. That child's
concentration time is maximum.
So this way, financial
stress is reduced for us.
Otherwise, we can be comfortable. Maternity
period is ugly, ugly, ugly, and tense because of
financial thing.  Is the main
finance is the main thing which causes problem
in any household, we have
our commitments, we have
responsibilities, when we know this kind of other
information and
put all this kind of insurance, that
responsibility is a shortcoming,
you get 70000 somewhere, so
yours is 70000 left, or somewhere,
basically it's on insurance,
you are working,
your company has given you that benefit, use the
insurance,
so I hope this video
is useful for you, if it is useful for you,
share it with other people who have other insurance, please like,
subscribe, subscribe, comment and
tell me your question there.  Will be more
than happy to help you all and
with and as I said before if you
want it in another language I can do it
for you if it's ok mix
both Kannada and fine I am so happy if you want it
specifically in Kannada do let
me know so thank you
for watching and thank you for
showering all your love on me have a
great day take care bye bye